The search for our beginning could lead to our end.
Prometheus is a science fiction, adventure,
mystery film directed by Ridley Scott.
A team of explorers discover a clue to the origins of mankind on Earth,
leading them on a journey to the darkest corners of the universe.
There, they must fight a terrifying battle to save the future of the human race.
Elizabeth Shaw, played by Noomi Rapace.
David, played by Michael Fassbender.
Meredith Vickers, played by Charlize Theron.
Janek, played by Idris Elba.
Peter Weyland, played by Guy Pearce.
Charlie Holloway, played by Logan Marshall-Green.
Prometheus is a 2012 science fiction horror film directed by Ridley
Scott and written by Jon Spaihts and Damon Lindelof.
It is the fifth installment of the Alien film series and features an ensemble cast including Noomi
Rapace, Michael Fassbender, Guy Pearce, Idris Elba, Logan Marshall-Green, and Charlize Theron.
Set in the late 21st century, the film centers on the crew of the spaceship Prometheus as it
follows a star map discovered among the artifacts of several ancient Earth cultures.
Seeking the origins of humanity, the crew arrives on a distant world and
discovers a threat that could cause human extinction.
Scott and director James Cameron developed ideas for a film that would serve as
a prequel to Scott's science-fiction horror film Alien (1979).
In 2002, the development of Alien vs.
Predator (2004) took precedence, and the project remained
dormant until 2009 when Scott again showed interest.
Spaihts wrote a script for a prequel to the events of the Alien films, but Scott opted
for a different direction to avoid repeating cues from those films.
In late 2010, Lindelof joined the project to rewrite Spaihts' script, and he and Scott developed a story
that precedes the story of Alien but is not directly connected to the original series.
According to Scott, although the film shares "strands of Alien's DNA," and takes place
in the same universe, Prometheus explores its own mythology and ideas.
Prometheus entered production in April 2010, with extensive design phases during which
the technology and creatures that the film required were developed.
Principal photography began in March 2011, with an
estimated $120–130 million budget.
The film was shot using 3D cameras throughout, almost entirely on practical sets,
and on location in England, Iceland, Scotland, Jordan, and Spain.
It was promoted with a marketing campaign that
included viral activities on the web.
Three videos featuring the film's leading actors in character, which expanded on elements of the
fictional universe, were released and met with a generally positive reception and awards.
Prometheus was released on June 1, 2012, in the United
Kingdom and on June 8, 2012, in North America.
The film earned generally positive reviews, receiving praise for the
designs, production values, and cast performances.
The film grossed over $403 million worldwide.
A sequel, Alien: Covenant, was released in May 2017.
The film explores themes of android, alien, space, creature, spin off.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and mind_bending.